<__top><zone region_type="body"><lex>A</lex> <ORGANIZATION><lex>People</lex><lex>'s</lex> <lex>Power</lex> <lex>Party</lex></ORGANIZATION> <lex>spokesman</lex> <lex>said</lex> <lex>Thursday</lex> <lex>a</lex> <lex>majority</lex> <lex>of</lex> <lex>its</lex>
<lex>members</lex> <lex>backed</lex> <lex>Samak</lex> <lex><ORGANIZATION>Sundaravej</ORGANIZATION></lex> <lex>as</lex> <lex>prime</lex> <lex>minister</lex><lex>.</lex> 

<lex>On</lex> <lex>Tuesday</lex><lex>,</lex> <lex>a</lex> <lex>constitutional</lex> <lex>court</lex> <lex>ruled</lex> <lex>that</lex> <lex>Mr.</lex> <lex><PERSON>Samak</PERSON></lex> <lex>must</lex> <lex>step</lex> <lex>down</lex>
<lex>as</lex> <lex>prime</lex> <lex>minister</lex> <lex>because</lex> <lex>he</lex> <lex>had</lex> <lex>violated</lex> <lex>the</lex> <lex>national</lex> <lex>charter</lex> <lex>by</lex>
<lex>hosting</lex> <lex>a</lex> <lex>television</lex> <lex>cooking</lex> <lex>show</lex> <lex>while</lex> <lex>in</lex> <lex>office</lex><lex>.</lex> 

<lex>The</lex> <lex>ruling</lex><lex>,</lex> <lex>however</lex><lex>,</lex> <lex>did</lex> <lex>not</lex> <lex>block</lex> <lex>his</lex> <lex>party</lex> <lex>from</lex> <lex>re-electing</lex> <lex>him</lex>
<lex>prime</lex> <lex>minister</lex><lex>.</lex> 

<lex>Parliament</lex> <lex>is</lex> <lex>to</lex> <lex>vote</lex> <lex>on</lex> <lex>the</lex> <lex>nomination</lex> <lex>Friday</lex><lex>.</lex>

<lex>The</lex> <lex>renomination</lex> <lex>could</lex> <lex>enrage</lex> <lex>anti-government</lex> <lex>protestors</lex> <lex>who</lex> <lex>demand</lex> <lex>he</lex>
<lex>resign</lex><lex>.</lex> <lex>Some</lex> <lex>political</lex> <lex>analysts</lex> <lex>and</lex> <lex>the</lex> <lex>business</lex> <lex>community</lex> <lex>also</lex> <lex>oppose</lex>
<lex>Mr.</lex> <lex><PERSON>Samak</PERSON></lex><lex>'s</lex> <lex>reappointment</lex><lex>,</lex> <lex>fearing</lex> <lex>it</lex> <lex>could</lex> <lex>lead</lex> <lex>to</lex> <lex>violence</lex> <lex>or</lex>
<lex>economic</lex> <lex>damage</lex><lex>.</lex> 

<lex>"</lex><lex><PERSON>Samak</PERSON></lex> <lex>is</lex> <lex>a</lex> <lex>bad</lex> <lex>idea</lex><lex>,"</lex> <lex>said</lex> <PERSON><lex>Sunai</lex> <lex>Pasuk</lex></PERSON><lex>,</lex><lex>a</lex> <lex>representative</lex> <lex>in</lex> <lex><LOCATION>Thailand</LOCATION></lex>
<lex>for</lex> <lex>Human</lex> <lex>Rights</lex> <lex>Watch</lex><lex>.</lex> <lex>"</lex><lex>There</lex> <lex>are</lex> <lex>competent</lex> <lex>people</lex> <lex>inside</lex> <lex>the</lex> <lex>party</lex> <lex>-</lex>
<lex>there</lex> <lex>are</lex> <lex>other</lex> <lex>senior</lex> <lex>politicians</lex> <lex>who</lex> <lex>could</lex> <lex>have</lex> <lex>been</lex> <lex>nominated</lex><lex>."</lex> 

<lex>The</lex> <lex><ORGANIZATION>PPP</ORGANIZATION></lex><lex>,</lex> <lex>which</lex> <lex>came</lex> <lex>to</lex> <lex>office</lex> <lex>after</lex> <lex>elections</lex> <lex>last</lex> <lex>December</lex><lex>,</lex> <lex>leads</lex> <lex>a</lex>
<lex>six-party</lex> <lex>coalition</lex> <lex>government</lex><lex>.</lex> 

<lex>The</lex> <lex>coalition</lex> <lex>members</lex> <lex>pledge</lex> <lex>to</lex> <lex>stand</lex> <lex>by</lex> <lex>the</lex> <lex><ORGANIZATION>PPP</ORGANIZATION></lex><lex>,</lex> <lex>despite</lex> <lex>weeks</lex> <lex>of</lex>
<lex>anti-government</lex> <lex>protests</lex><lex>,</lex> <lex>which</lex> <lex>have</lex> <lex>brought</lex> <lex>much</lex> <lex>of</lex> <lex>the</lex> <lex>country</lex><lex>'s</lex>
<lex>administration</lex> <lex>to</lex> <lex>a</lex> <lex>standstill</lex><lex>.</lex> 

<lex>The</lex> <lex>opposition</lex><lex>,</lex> <lex>led</lex> <lex>the</lex> <lex>People</lex><lex>'s</lex> <lex><ORGANIZATION>Alliance</ORGANIZATION></lex> <lex>for</lex> <lex>Democracy</lex><lex>,</lex> <lex>accuse</lex>
<lex>Mr.</lex> <lex><PERSON>Samak</PERSON></lex> <lex>and</lex> <lex>the</lex> <lex><ORGANIZATION>PPP</ORGANIZATION></lex> <lex>of</lex> <lex>acting</lex> <lex>for</lex> <lex>former</lex> <lex>Prime</lex> <lex>Minister</lex> <PERSON><lex>Thaksin</lex>
<lex>Shinawatra</lex></PERSON><lex>,</lex> <lex>who</lex> <lex>was</lex> <lex>ousted</lex> <lex>in</lex> <lex>a</lex> <lex>coup</lex> <lex>two</lex> <lex>years</lex> <lex>ago</lex><lex>.</lex> <lex>His</lex> <lex>critics</lex>
<lex>consider</lex> <lex>him</lex> <lex>corrupt</lex> <lex>and</lex> <lex>authoritarian</lex><lex>.</lex> 

<lex>Mr.</lex> <lex><PERSON>Thaksin</PERSON></lex> <lex>fled</lex> <lex>to</lex> <lex><LOCATION>Britain</LOCATION></lex> <lex>in</lex> <lex>August</lex> <lex>to</lex> <lex>avoid</lex> <lex>trial</lex> <lex>on</lex> <lex>corruption</lex>
<lex>charges</lex><lex>.</lex> <lex>But</lex> <lex>Thai</lex> <lex>news</lex> <lex>media</lex> <lex>reported</lex> <lex>extensively</lex> <lex>Thursday</lex> <lex>that</lex>
<lex>Mr.</lex> <lex><PERSON>Thaksin</PERSON></lex> <lex>had</lex> <lex>told</lex> <lex><ORGANIZATION>PPP</ORGANIZATION></lex> <lex>leaders</lex> <lex>he</lex> <lex>wanted</lex> <lex>Mr.</lex> <lex><PERSON>Samak</PERSON></lex> <lex>to</lex> <lex>remain</lex> <lex>in</lex>
<lex>office</lex><lex>.</lex> 

<lex><PERSON>Sunai</PERSON></lex> <lex>says</lex> <lex>if</lex> <lex>that</lex> <lex>is</lex> <lex>true</lex><lex>,</lex> <lex>it</lex> <lex>would</lex> <lex>indicate</lex> <lex>that</lex> <lex>Mr.</lex> <lex><PERSON>Thaksin</PERSON></lex> <lex>is</lex>
<lex>challenging</lex> <lex>the</lex> <lex>courts</lex><lex>.</lex> 

<lex>"</lex><lex>I</lex> <lex>could</lex> <lex>only</lex> <lex>guess</lex> <lex><PERSON>Thaksin</PERSON></lex> <lex>might</lex> <lex>have</lex> <lex>felt</lex> <lex>that</lex> <lex>he</lex> <lex>and</lex> <lex>his</lex> <lex>party</lex> <lex>have</lex>
<lex>been</lex> <lex>hard</lex> <lex>done</lex> <lex>by</lex><lex>,</lex> <lex>by</lex> <lex>the</lex> <lex>judiciary</lex> <lex>so</lex> <lex>this</lex> <lex>is</lex> <lex>moment</lex> <lex>of</lex> <lex>defiance</lex><lex>,"</lex>
<lex>added</lex> <PERSON><lex>Sunai</lex><lex>.</lex></PERSON> 

<lex>Also</lex> <lex>Thursday</lex><lex>,</lex> <lex><LOCATION>Thailand</LOCATION></lex><lex>'s</lex> <lex>army</lex> <lex>chief</lex> <lex>called</lex> <lex>on</lex> <lex>the</lex> <lex>government</lex> <lex>to</lex>
<lex>revoke</lex> <lex>the</lex> <lex>state</lex> <lex>of</lex> <lex>emergency</lex> <lex>that</lex> <lex>was</lex> <lex>imposed</lex> <lex>last</lex> <lex>week</lex> <lex>after</lex> <lex>clashes</lex>
<lex>between</lex> <lex>pro-government</lex> <lex>and</lex> <lex>anti-government</lex> <lex>protestors</lex><lex>.</lex> 

<lex>Opinion</lex> <lex>polls</lex> <lex>show</lex> <lex>a</lex> <lex>majority</lex> <lex>of</lex> <lex>voters</lex> <lex>favor</lex> <lex>new</lex> <lex>elections</lex> <lex>to</lex> <lex>end</lex> <lex>the</lex>
<lex>political</lex> <lex>deadlock</lex><lex>.</lex> 
</zone></__top>