<__top>Private sector intelligence analysts have made public for the first
time an apparent missile base in <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION>. A report to be published
next week by <PERSON>Jane</PERSON>'s Defense Weekly is expected to unveil satellite
images of the North Korean facility near <LOCATION>Podong-ni</LOCATION>. Analysts say it
appears designed to accommodate test launches of long-range missiles. 

<LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> has poured a large amount of its economic output into
missile development for decades. It has about 800 missiles capable of
hitting <LOCATION>South Korea</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION>, and test-fired a missile directly over
Japanese territory in 1998. <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> test-fired a long-range
missile in 2006, a few months before it conducted its first test
explosion of a nuclear weapon. 

<PERSON>David Asher</PERSON> is a former coordinator of <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> policy at the
<LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>State Department</ORGANIZATION>. During a visit to <LOCATION>Seoul</LOCATION> this week, he said
there are signs <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> may be contemplating more missile tests. 

"Last week there was a statement by the <ORGANIZATION>KCNA</ORGANIZATION>, the <LOCATION>[North]</LOCATION> Korean news
agency ... it stated that <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> has the right to test a
satellite. <PERSON>Well</PERSON>, this is exactly what they did before they tested the
<ORGANIZATION>Taepodong</ORGANIZATION> a few years ago. And I would be very concerned, personally,
just based on that, that they are going to do this again," said
<ORGANIZATION>Asher</ORGANIZATION>. 

South Korean Defense Minister <PERSON>Lee Sang-hee</PERSON> was quoted in local media
as saying he is aware of the missile base, and believes it is 80
percent complete. Defense Minister <PERSON>Lee</PERSON> was quoted as saying there have
been no unusual moves by the <ORGANIZATION>North</ORGANIZATION>'s military, amid the possibly
not taking any immediate steps to raise its level of defense alert. 

<LOCATION>South Korea</LOCATION>'s intelligence agency revealed this week its belief the
<ORGANIZATION>North</ORGANIZATION>'s leader is recovering from a cerebral hemorrhage, or stroke, he
suffered last month. North Korean officials reject the reports as a
worthless conspiracy. Nonetheless, <ORGANIZATION>Kim Jong Il</ORGANIZATION> has not been seen in
public since August 14. 

<PERSON>Kim Jong Il</PERSON> has absolute personal control of <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION>'s secretive
government. <PERSON>He</PERSON> has never publicly named a successor. Leaders view any
compromise of his health as potentially destabilizing to the North
Korean system - and even to peace on the Korean peninsula. 

Brian Myers specializes in <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION>'s propaganda and official
communications at <LOCATION>South Korea</LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION>Dongseo University</ORGANIZATION>. He says <LOCATION>North
Korea</LOCATION>'s domestic media is absolutely silent about international
reports on their leader's health. 

"What we can expect are editorials that condemn the rest of the world
for making baseless rumors, but I do not think the North Korean press
will explain to the people what those rumors are," he said. 

<PERSON>He</PERSON> says health problems may put a dent in the <ORGANIZATION>North</ORGANIZATION>'s efforts to
portray Kim <PERSON>Jong Il</PERSON> as an all-powerful leader. 

"It does compromise his image because North Korean propaganda has
always praised <ORGANIZATION>Kim Jong Il</ORGANIZATION> for his sturdy constitution, and compared
it favorably to the poor health of other leaders," he said. 

<PERSON>He</PERSON> says average <LOCATION>North Koreans</LOCATION> are probably aware of their leader's
health situation, via broadcast and cell phone technology, as well as
robust business contact with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION>. 
</__top>