<__top>A <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> newspaper is reporting that President <PERSON>George Bush</PERSON> gave secret
orders in July authorizing U.S. armed forces to carry out ground
assaults in <LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION> without seeking approval from <LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION>'s
government. 

The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> newspaper quotes senior <ORGANIZATION>U.S.</ORGANIZATION> officials who said the
military will notify <LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION>'s government when it conducts raids, but
will not seek its permission. 

The officials, who insisted on remaining anonymous, said the orders
are part of a broader push to assert <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> control over the
<LOCATION>Afghan-Pakistani</LOCATION> border, considered a stronghold for the <LOCATION>Taliban</LOCATION> and
<LOCATION>al-Qaida</LOCATION><LOCATION>.</LOCATION> 

<LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION>'s army chief, General <PERSON>Ashfaq Kayani</PERSON>, criticized Wednesday a
recent series of suspected <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> raids in <LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION>, vowing to defend
the country's sovereignty "at all costs." <LOCATION>Pakistani</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Prime Minister
Yousuf Raza</ORGANIZATION> Gilani Thursday said the army chief's statement reflects
government views. 

In related news, the chief of the <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> military says his new strategy
for the war in <LOCATION>Afghanistan</LOCATION> will tackle what he calls the "common
insurgency" in the tribal areas on both sides of the <LOCATION>Afghan-Pakistani</LOCATION>
border. 

said Wednesday the <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> and its allies cannot "kill our way to
victory" in <LOCATION>Afghanistan</LOCATION>. He said <PERSON>Afghanistan</PERSON> needs more international
help to improve its rule of law and economic development. 

President <PERSON>Bush</PERSON> announced Tuesday that he will increase <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> troop
levels in <LOCATION>Afghanistan</LOCATION> by 1,500 by February. <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> commanders there have
requested about 10,000 additional troops. 
</__top>