<__top>Russian Prime Minister <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> has strongly defended the
Russian military incursion into <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION>, but says <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> has no
intention of annexing any territory of former Soviet republics. 

<PERSON>Mr. Putin</PERSON>, speaking Thursday in southern Russia, said <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> has no
"imperial ambitions" for <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION>, despite what he said were Western
accusations to the contrary. 

Separately Thursday, Russian news reports say President <PERSON>Dmitri
Medvedev</PERSON> again accused <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> of military aggression last month
against <ORGANIZATION>the Georgian</ORGANIZATION> breakaway territory of <LOCATION>South Ossetia</LOCATION>. 

Mr. <PERSON>Medvedev</PERSON> said the <LOCATION>Georgian</LOCATION> move against South Ossetia August 7
triggered Russia's military incursion and has made the modernization
of the Russian military a top priority. 

Earlier Thursday, the pro-Russian separatist leader in <LOCATION>South Ossetia</LOCATION>
said the <LOCATION>Georgian</LOCATION> region will not seek to become part of Russia,
despite earlier reports to the contrary. 

Russian news agencies quoted Eduard Kokoity earlier as saying <ORGANIZATION>South
Ossetia</ORGANIZATION> is to join the <ORGANIZATION>North</ORGANIZATION> Ossetian region of Russia. He later told
journalists he was misquoted. 

<PERSON>Russia</PERSON> has defied a host of Western governments by recognizing South
Ossetia and a second breakaway region, <LOCATION>Abkhazia</LOCATION>, as independent
states. <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> moved earlier this week to establish diplomatic ties
with both territories. 

Abkhazian leader <PERSON>Sergei Bagapsh</PERSON> said his region hopes to join the
<ORGANIZATION>Russian-Belarus Union State</ORGANIZATION>. 

Russian forces pushed into <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> last month after the <LOCATION>Georgian</LOCATION>
military tried to retake control of <LOCATION>South Ossetia</LOCATION>. Russia said it had
to protect its citizens in the pro-Russian region. 
</__top>