<__top>An American newspaper says <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Pakistani</LOCATION> officials are shifting
tactics in their search for al-Qaida leader <PERSON>Osama bin Laden</PERSON>,
intensifying the use of unmanned, but lethal, spy planes in western
<LOCATION>Pakistan.</LOCATION> 

The <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> Post Wednesday quotes the officials as saying the
number of missile attacks by pilotless Predator drones in <LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION> has
more than tripled in the past year. They say <LOCATION>Pakistani</LOCATION> officials
reported 11 such strikes this year, compared to three strikes in
2007. 

The Post says officials involved in the operations call the attacks
part of a renewed effort to cripple <LOCATION>al-Qaida</LOCATION>'s central command. They
say officials are targeting top al-Qaida members in the hope that they
could lead authorities to bin <LOCATION>Laden.</LOCATION> 

The <PERSON>Bush</PERSON> administration did not immediately comment on the <ORGANIZATION>report.</ORGANIZATION> But
<ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman Dana <LOCATION>Perino</LOCATION> Wednesday said President <PERSON>Bush</PERSON> has
not given up on efforts to track down bin <LOCATION>Laden</LOCATION> and his followers. 

<LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> officials have said they suspect bin <LOCATION>Laden</LOCATION> and other al-Qaida
leaders are hiding in <LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION>'s tribal regions along the <ORGANIZATION>Afghan
border.</ORGANIZATION> 

The <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> has used drones to target militants along <LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION>'s
border with <LOCATION>Afghanistan</LOCATION> in the past. 

Since late August there have been at least five suspected <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> missile
strikes against militant targets in <LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION>'s <ORGANIZATION>North and South
Waziristan</ORGANIZATION> regions. <PERSON>Afghan</PERSON>, <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION>NATO</ORGANIZATION> officials say the regions
act as <LOCATION>Taliban</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>al-Qaida</LOCATION> sanctuaries. 

The Post says <ORGANIZATION>U.S.</ORGANIZATION> officials attribute their failure to find bin Laden
mostly to an inability to develop intelligence informants in
<LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION>'s tribal regions. 
</__top>