<__top>Zimbabwean political leaders are set to hold a fourth day of
power-sharing talks Thursday, and it remains unclear how close they
are to a deal. 

At the end of Wednesday's talks in the capital, <PERSON>Harare</PERSON>, President
<PERSON>Robert Mugabe</PERSON> called the progress "encouraging" and said he hopes all
parties will sign an agreement Friday. 

Main opposition leader <PERSON>Morgan Tsvangirai</PERSON> said there is very little
work left to do in the negotiations. 

progress was made in Wednesday's talks, and that prospects for a deal
this week appear "slim." 

The sides are stuck on the question of how President <PERSON>Mugabe</PERSON> and
<LOCATION>Tsvangirai</LOCATION> would divide power in a national unity government. 

South African President <PERSON>Thabo Mbeki</PERSON> is mediating the talks under a
mandate from the <ORGANIZATION>Southern African Development Community.</ORGANIZATION> 

Mr. <PERSON>Mbeki</PERSON> put off a planned trip to <LOCATION>Swaziland</LOCATION> for a second day
Thursday so he can stay in <LOCATION>Harare</LOCATION>. The South African president had
been scheduled to report on the talks to the <ORGANIZATION>SADC</ORGANIZATION>'s security
committee. 

The talks appeared deadlocked a week ago, after <ORGANIZATION>Tsvangirai</ORGANIZATION> rejected a
proposal that would have given him a largely ceremonial post as prime
minister. 

Despite this week's progress, The <ORGANIZATION>Herald</ORGANIZATION> says Mr. <PERSON>Mugabe</PERSON> has warned he
will form a new government by the end the week no matter what
transpires in the negotiations. 

<PERSON>Tsvangirai</PERSON>'s party, the Movement for Democratic Change, gained control
of parliament in the March parliamentary elections, and he won more
votes than Mr. <PERSON>Mugabe</PERSON> in the presidential poll. 

But official results showed Tsvangirai falling short of a majority,
and he boycotted a runoff presidential election because of
state-sponsored attacks on his supporters. 

Mr. <PERSON>Mugabe</PERSON> won the uncontested runoff, extending his nearly 30-year
rule. 

The parties are under international pressure to reach a power-sharing
deal so <LOCATION>Zimbabwe</LOCATION> can begin recovering from its deep economic
crisis. The country is suffering food and fuel shortages that have
helped drive up inflation to an estimated 11 million percent. 
</__top>