{"signal": "Residents along the coastal region of the southwestern U.S. state of\nTexas have begun evacuating their homes to escape the potential\nonslaught of Hurricane Ike. \n\nThe National Hurricane Center says Ike is traveling through the Gulf\nof Mexico carrying maximum sustained winds of 160 kilometers an hour,\nmaking it a Category Two hurricane.  Forecasters say Ike could evolve\ninto a much stronger Category Three storm later Thursday or Friday.  \n\nThey say the center of the storm could hit the northwestern coast of\nthe Gulf of Mexico late Friday. \n\nAuthorities in the coastal city of Galveston have already issued a\nmandatory evacuation order, and have begun transporting ill and\nelderly residents to temporary shelters in the cities of San Antonio\nand Dallas. \n\nPresident George Bush has declared a state of emergency in Texas,\nfreeing up federal resources and allowing federal authorities to\ncoordinate disaster efforts.  \n\nTexas Governor Rick Perry declared 88 coastal counties as disaster\nareas.  \n\nOil companies are evacuating workers from their offshore drilling\nplatforms.  \n\nTropical storm warnings have been issued for the coastal areas of\nMississippi, Alabama and Louisiana, including New Orleans.  \n\nThe storm killed at least four people in Cuba and forced more than one\nmillion people to evacuate.  \n\nIn Haiti, Ike killed about 70 people, caused widespread flooding and\nleft residents desperate for food and water.  Hundreds of people have\nbeen killed in Haiti in storms in recent weeks.   \n", "asets": [{"hasID": false, "type": "lex", "attrs": [], "annots": [[0, 9], [10, 15], [16, 19], [20, 27], [28, 34], [35, 37], [38, 41], [42, 54], [55, 59], [60, 65], [66, 68], [69, 74], [75, 79], [80, 85], [86, 96], [97, 102], [103, 108], [109, 111], [112, 118], [119, 122], [123, 132], [133, 142], [143, 145], [146, 155], [156, 159], [159, 160], [163, 166], [167, 175], [176, 185], [186, 192], [193, 197], [198, 201], [202, 204], [205, 214], [215, 222], [223, 226], [227, 231], [232, 234], [235, 241], [242, 250], [251, 258], [259, 268], [269, 274], [275, 277], [278, 281], [282, 292], [293, 295], [296, 300], [300, 301], [302, 308], [309, 311], [312, 313], [314, 322], [323, 326], [327, 336], [336, 337], [339, 350], [351, 354], [355, 358], [359, 364], [365, 371], [372, 376], [377, 378], [379, 383], [384, 392], [393, 401], [402, 407], [408, 413], [414, 419], [420, 428], [429, 431], [432, 438], [438, 439], [443, 447], [448, 451], [452, 455], [456, 462], [463, 465], [466, 469], [470, 475], [476, 481], [482, 485], [486, 489], [490, 502], [503, 508], [509, 511], [512, 515], [516, 520], [521, 523], [524, 530], [531, 535], [536, 542], [542, 543], [546, 557], [558, 560], [561, 564], [565, 572], [573, 577], [578, 580], [581, 590], [591, 595], [596, 603], [604, 610], [611, 612], [613, 622], [623, 633], [634, 639], [639, 640], [641, 644], [645, 649], [650, 655], [656, 668], [669, 672], [673, 676], [677, 684], [685, 694], [695, 697], [698, 707], [708, 716], [717, 719], [720, 723], [724, 730], [731, 733], [734, 737], [738, 745], [746, 749], [750, 756], [756, 757], [760, 769], [770, 776], [777, 781], [782, 785], [786, 794], [795, 796], [797, 802], [803, 805], [806, 815], [816, 818], [819, 824], [824, 825], [826, 833], [834, 836], [837, 844], [845, 854], [855, 858], [859, 867], [868, 875], [876, 887], [888, 890], [891, 901], [902, 910], [911, 918], [918, 919], [923, 928], [929, 937], [938, 942], [943, 948], [949, 957], [958, 960], [961, 968], [969, 977], [978, 980], [981, 989], [990, 995], [995, 996], [1000, 1003], [1004, 1013], [1014, 1017], [1018, 1028], [1029, 1036], [1037, 1041], [1042, 1047], [1048, 1056], [1057, 1065], [1066, 1075], [1075, 1076], [1080, 1088], [1089, 1094], [1095, 1103], [1104, 1108], [1109, 1113], [1114, 1120], [1121, 1124], [1125, 1128], [1129, 1136], [1137, 1142], [1143, 1145], [1146, 1157], [1157, 1158], [1159, 1166], [1167, 1170], [1171, 1180], [1180, 1181], [1182, 1191], [1192, 1195], [1196, 1203], [1203, 1204], [1208, 1211], [1212, 1217], [1218, 1224], [1225, 1227], [1228, 1233], [1234, 1238], [1239, 1245], [1246, 1248], [1249, 1253], [1254, 1257], [1258, 1264], [1265, 1269], [1270, 1274], [1275, 1278], [1279, 1286], [1287, 1293], [1294, 1296], [1297, 1305], [1305, 1306], [1310, 1312], [1313, 1318], [1318, 1319], [1320, 1323], [1324, 1330], [1331, 1336], [1337, 1339], [1340, 1346], [1346, 1347], [1348, 1354], [1355, 1365], [1366, 1374], [1375, 1378], [1379, 1383], [1384, 1393], [1394, 1403], [1404, 1407], [1408, 1412], [1413, 1416], [1417, 1422], [1422, 1423], [1425, 1433], [1434, 1436], [1437, 1443], [1444, 1448], [1449, 1453], [1454, 1460], [1461, 1463], [1464, 1469], [1470, 1472], [1473, 1479], [1480, 1482], [1483, 1489], [1490, 1495], [1495, 1496]], "hasSpan": true}, {"hasID": false, "type": "zone", "attrs": [{"type": "string", "name": "region_type"}], "annots": [[0, 1500, "body"]], "hasSpan": true}, {"hasID": false, "type": "ENAMEX", "attrs": [{"type": "string", "name": "type"}], "annots": [[42, 59, "LOCATION"], [69, 74, "LOCATION"], [198, 201, "PERSON"], [223, 231, "ORGANIZATION"], [355, 358, "ORGANIZATION"], [490, 502, "ORGANIZATION"], [512, 520, "ORGANIZATION"], [524, 530, "LOCATION"], [581, 590, "LOCATION"], [734, 745, "LOCATION"], [750, 756, "LOCATION"], [770, 781, "PERSON"], [819, 824, "LOCATION"], [923, 928, "LOCATION"], [938, 948, "PERSON"], [1080, 1088, "ORGANIZATION"], [1146, 1158, "LOCATION"], [1159, 1166, "LOCATION"], [1171, 1180, "LOCATION"], [1192, 1203, "LOCATION"], [1249, 1253, "LOCATION"], [1297, 1306, "ORGANIZATION"], [1313, 1318, "LOCATION"], [1464, 1469, "LOCATION"]], "hasSpan": true}, {"hasID": false, "type": "SEGMENT", "attrs": [{"type": "string", "name": "status"}, {"type": "string", "name": "annotator"}], "annots": [[0, 1500, "reconciled", "GOLD_STANDARD"]], "hasSpan": true}], "version": 2, "metadata": {"phasesDone": ["tokenize", "tag", "zone"]}}